Louis Ries

406 Mills Lane, New Albany, IN 47150 Cell: 502-836-9588 • <u>LSRies0304@Gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn.com/in/pallen0304</u> • github.com/pallen0304

Professional Summary

Self-directed and motivated Software Engineer with expertise in all aspects of the software development life cycle, including requirements analysis, design, development, and production support. Fluent in Java, VB.Net, and C# programming languages. Currently studying .Net Core 2.0, Angular 5, Entity Framework, and Microsoft Azure Development.

Skills

- ASP.Net, C#, Java, VB.Net
- JavaScript, jQuery, Angular 2+
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- MS SQL, MySQL, PL/SQL
- MS Excel, MS Access

- Full Lifecycle Development (SDLC)
- Code Reviews
- Test-Driven Development
- Agile Methodologies

Education

2015-2018 Bachelors of Science in Business Administration in Computer Information Systems University of Louisville – 2301 S 3RD Street, Louisville, Kentucky 40292

- GPA 3.08
- Emphasis in Web Development
- Expected Graduation August 2018

2017 Associate of General Studies in General Studies

Ivy Tech State College - One W 26Th St. Box 1763 Indianapolis, IN 46206

2011-2015 **Academic Honors Diploma**

New Albany High School - 1020 Vincennes St, New Albany, IN 47150

Experience

UPS Global Operations Center, Louisville, Kentucky **Application Developer**, May 8th, 2017 – Current

- Developing Internal Applications using ASP.Net/C# Web Forms.
- Developing Front-End Web Applications using Angular 4 with Typescript.

Application Developer, May 16th, 2016 – Dec 30th, 2016

- Migrated ASP Classic/VB6 WinForms to ASP.Net/C# Web Forms.
- Migrated Crystal Reports to Office Open XML for usage with MS Excel.
- Developed and supported Web Form applications for Labor Administration at UPS.

Attended Software Development Conference Code PaLOUsa 2013-2018 Speaker at Software Development Conference Code PaLOUsa in 2018 Active Member of Louisville .Net Developers Meetup Group since Nov 15th, 2012 University of Evansville Programming Competition 2013-2015 Indiana University – Purdue University Indianapolis Programming Competition 2015 Ivy Tech Community College Programming Competition 2013

Community

Indiana State 4-H Purdue
Shamrocks Club – 10 years
Junior Leaders – 3 years
Tenure Award
Member of the Year 2015